<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2018-09-12T22:05:15-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">ElephWebb.io</title><subtitle>Personal Lab</subtitle><author><name>elephwebb</name></author><entry><title type="html">Debugging Javascript as a Ninja</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-04-19-debugging-js-like-a-ninja/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Debugging Javascript as a Ninja" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/debugging-js-like-a-ninja</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-04-19-debugging-js-like-a-ninja/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;prepare-your-environment&quot;&gt;Prepare your Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistakes happen and by no chance you will write down code without make small tiny mistakes that were not a mistake initially. So why not have a automated way to catch them all and display before even save/compile your code?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that is the first step on debugging your code, pre debug automatically using linters, a linters are tools with bunch of rules pre-defined using code standards, and is quite easy to set linters inside our favorite editor(sublime, atom, visual studio code, etc), the linters can also be runned in our command-line console, which is fantastic because we can set these bunch of rules that we want to be followed everytime the whole code is built and deployed to a QA environment, and is fantastic because we assure that not only our code is being “linted” to check mistakes, inconsistences but everyone that colaborate to the project, combining these linters with a nice tests suite stack, the bugs in your system can reduce drastically, which means less time debugging “ghost” mistakes and less time refactoring/improving features and adding more value to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also would like to mention that debugg smartly is part of a test-driven environment, because if you think write down tests, whether they are functional, acceptance, smokey, end-to-end whatever, the mindset is what counts, think the scenario, figure out what could be an expected error, make the famous Green-red-Green cycle, make it pass with minimal solution, then make it fails intentionally/expectedly, then refactor the code make it pass. Which reduce the time debugging the error in the long run. And a last think, debugging is not google the error, but think the error, rollback to a safe point where everything is working, try to expect the result, code in small pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I share some secret techniquees by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/profile/Marek-Kirejczyk&quot;&gt;Marek Kirejczyk, (VP of Engineering at DaftCode&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://qr.ae/TU16Nn&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt; where he says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Debug using binary search on your code. You can also do binary search your repository history (see git bisect). This technique can be very helpful when looking for bugs in the code.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Undo the last change if you brake something. Because you make small steps and you keep app covered wit tests, you should be able quickly notice if you break something. Just undo the recent change and start step from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-atom-and-eslint&quot;&gt;Setting Atom and EsLint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is quick video by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qhuFviJn-es&quot;&gt;Harry Wolff&lt;/a&gt;shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; in their &lt;a href=&quot;'https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8butISFwT-Wl7EV0hUK0BQ'&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complement the video, because, it turns down that in Atom didn’t Lint the errors up on only following Harry’s video, not sure why, besides he uses Visual Studio Code and in VSCode it worked out - tested. &lt;a href=&quot;What is ESLint? How do I set it up on Atom?&quot;&gt;https://hackernoon.com/what-is-eslint-how-do-i-set-it-up-on-atom-70f270f57296&lt;/a&gt;. One detail, Atom recognizes every spaces inside the Tabs, not really Tabs, so in the eslintrc.json file use {“indent”: { “errors”, 2 } } if you use Tabs like me instead of spaces to make your identation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are funny sceneres related to this Tab versus Spaces in Sillicon Valley’s Serie : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V7PLxL8jIl8&quot;&gt;I will update show the videos here instead of links to YouTube&lt;/a&gt;… one day. :-) 5 min break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue&quot;&gt;Continue…&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>elephwebb</name></author><category term="posts" /><category term="javascript" /><category term="eslint" /><category term="atom" /><summary type="html">Prepare your Environment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Divign into Searchability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-04-18-diving-into-searchability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Divign into Searchability" /><published>2018-04-18T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2018-04-18T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/diving-into-searchability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-04-18-diving-into-searchability/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-preparing&quot;&gt;Still preparing…&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>elephwebb</name></author><category term="posts" /><summary type="html">Still preparing…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Test-Driven REST Subscription API</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-02-19-building-a-test-driven-rest-subscription-api/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Test-Driven REST Subscription API" /><published>2018-02-19T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2017-12-05T21:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/building-a-test-driven-rest-subscription-api</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018-02-19-building-a-test-driven-rest-subscription-api/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-preparing-the-post-and-files&quot;&gt;Still preparing the post and files…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-will-build&quot;&gt;What we will build?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to build a Subscription System API for Online Services using &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/understanding/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; and PHP Laravel 5.6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The API will implement different Payment Gateways like (Stripe and PayPal), it contains User Authentication and Registration using OAuth - JWT protocol for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code source and online API can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elephwebb/laravel-test-driven-rest-api&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and you can contribute if you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/FVryIUaW&quot;&gt;KANBAN&lt;/a&gt; of the project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>elephwebb</name></author><category term="posts" /><category term="test-driven" /><category term="rest" /><category term="laravel" /><summary type="html">Using best practices</summary></entry></feed>